assembly a low-level programming language designed to simplify the
汇编 一种低级编程语言，旨在简化
instructions fed into a computer's cpu in other words it's a human-readable
输入计算机 cpu的指令，换句话说，它
abstraction on top of machine code so programmers don't have to manually count
是机器代码之上的人类可读抽象，因此程序员不必手动计算
ones and zeroes the first assembly language was created by kathleen booth
1 和 0 第一个汇编语言是由 kathleen
in 1947 for the all-purpose electronic computer over the next decade it evolved
于 1947 年为通用电子计算机展台，在接下来的十年里，它演变
into many different formats to power the super computers of the day like the ibm
成许多不同的格式，为当时的超级计算机提供动力，例如 ibm
7090 which had a 20 million dollar price tag in today's dollars writing code and
7090，以今天的美元计算，其标价为 2000 万美元，并且
assembly was standard until the emergence of high level languages like
装配是标准配置 直到
fortran a few years later however assembly is still used today for direct
几年后出现了像 fortran 这样的高级语言，但是今天仍然使用汇编来直接
access to the bare metal hardware and to address low-level performance issues
访问裸机硬件并解决
often on device drivers and embedded systems and it's also used to run native
设备驱动程序和嵌入式系统上经常出现的低级性能问题，它还用于运行本机
software in a web browser via webassembly what's tricky is that each
软件 在通过 webassembly 的 Web 浏览器中，棘手的是每种
assembly language only works on a specific cpu architecture like arm for
汇编语言只适用于特定的 cpu 架构，如 ar  m 用于
apple silicon and raspberry pi or x86 for intel chips to get started you'll
苹果硅和树莓派或 x86用于英特尔芯片 开始您
first need an assembler like the net wide assembler for x86 chips an assembly
首先需要一个汇编器，例如用于 x86 芯片的网络宽汇编器 一个汇编
program is divided into three sections the text section contains the actual
程序分为三个部分 文本部分按惯例包含程序的实际
logic for the program by convention it contains an entry point called start
逻辑 它包含一个名为 start 的入口点
which is where the code will start executing next we have the block
，这是代码接下来将开始执行的地方 我们有块
starting symbol section which contains variables that might change throughout
起始符号部分，其中包含可能
the lifecycle of the app and finally the data section is where we can initialize
在应用程序的整个生命周期中发生变化的变量，最后数据部分是我们可以初始化
constants or data that does not change to declare a constant like a string we
常量或数据的地方 不改变声明像字符串一样的常量，我们
start with a label then use db for defined byte to place the hello world
以标签开头，然后使用 db定义字节，将 hello world
string into memory by itself it doesn't do anything and to print it to the
字符串本身放入内存它不做任何事情并将其打印到
standard output we will also need it to length we can use equate to convert a
标准输出，我们也需要它长度我们可以使用equate将
symbol into a constant the dollar sign will subtract the current position from
符号转换为常数美元符号
the hello label providing the length of the string and now these constants can
将从hello标签中减去当前位置提供字符串a的长度 现在
be referenced from the start label in the main program each line of code
可以从主程序的开始标签中引用这些常量，每行代码都
contains an instruction along with one or more operands and there are hundreds
包含一条指令以及一个或多个操作数，现在
of instructions built into the language now to perform operations quickly the
语言中内置了数百条指令来快速执行操作，
cpu has a limited number of registers which are like 64-bit chunks of memory
cpu 的数量有限寄存器就像
built directly into the cpu instead of the ram we can insert data into a
直接内置在 cpu 而不是 ram 中的 64 位内存块 我们可以使用移动指令将数据插入到
register with the move instruction by providing operands for the register name
寄存器中，方法是提供寄存器名称的操作数
and the data to store there in this case number one is used because it
和要存储在那里的数据，在这种情况下使用第一个 因为它
corresponds to system write on linux next we need to tell the system where to
对应于 linux 上的系统写入，所以我们需要告诉系统在哪里
write in which case we'll move one into the rdi register which corresponds to
写入，在这种情况下，我们会将一个移动到 rdi 寄存器中，该寄存器对应
the standard output in the terminal the next register stores the message to
于终端中的标准输出，下一个寄存器将消息
right along with its length now execute the code stored in the cpu by calling
与其一起存储到右侧 length 现在通过调用操作系统内核来执行存储在 cpu 中的代码
the operating system kernel almost done but we'll get a segmentation fault if we
几乎完成了，但是如果我们此时尝试运行它，我们会遇到分段错误
try to run it at this point update the racks register with 60 for system exit
将机架寄存器更新为 60 以退出系统，
and provide an error code of zero for a success now use the assembler to compile
并提供零错误代码以表示成功 现在使用汇编
or assemble your code into an object file then use the linker to convert it
器将代码编译或汇编到目标文件中，然后使用链接器将其
into the final executable this has been assembly language in 100 seconds if you
转换为最终的可执行文件，这是汇编语言 100秒如果你
want to see more short videos like this hit the like button and subscribe thanks
想看更多这样的短视频点击喜欢按钮并订阅
for watching and i will see you in the next one
感谢观看，我会在下一个看到你